http://www.odnetwork.org/page/privacy

OD Network Data Privacy Policy - OD Network
This website uses cookies to store information on your computer. Some of these cookies are used for visitor analysis, others are essential to making our site function properly and improve the user experience. By using this site, you consent to the placement of these cookies. Click Accept to consent and dismiss this message or Deny to leave this website. Read our Privacy Statement for more.
Accept
Deny
Join OD Network   |   Calendar   |   Site Search   |   Print Page   |   Sign In
Home
AboutMission, Vision, Purpose2017-2020 Strategic Plan (PDF)LeadershipHistory of OD
What Is OD?
Hall of Fame
Award WinnersLifetime AchievementOrganizational Excellence in ODOutstanding Achievement in Global WorkOutstanding Article of the YearService to the OD NetworkSharing the WealthCommunicating OD KnowledgeEmerging PractitionerOutstanding Regional OD AwardMembers' Choice
Contact Us
Join
Join or RenewMember BenefitsWelcome Group ProgramOD Education Association (ODEA)
Learn
What Is OD?Global OD Competency Framework™Dialogic ODDEI ResourcesMentoring ProgramVirtual Learning
On-Demand WebinarsUpcoming Webinars
Publications
Organization Development ReviewOD Network ConnectionsNetwork NewsSubmit an ArticleHandbook for Strategic HROrganization Development in Practice
Emerging PractitionersOD ResourcesOnline Store
Conference
Call for ProposalsAward NominationsAward WinnersPast Conferences
Network
Event CalendarFind an OD ConsultantJob ExchangeVolunteerMember RecognitionAdvertising OpportunitiesBusiness PartnersRegional NetworksInternational Affiliates
ODN EuropeSouth African ODNOD Network JapanODN Singapore
Edit This Favorite
Name:
Category:
Share:
Yes
No, Keep Private
OD Network Data Privacy Policy
Introduction The Organization Development Network (“OD Network”) is a global association of OD practitioners and scholars. We understand that you are aware of and care about your own personal privacy interests, and we take that seriously.
This privacy policy describes our policies and practices regarding collection and use of your personal data, and sets forth your privacy rights. We recognize that information privacy is an ongoing responsibility, and so we will continue to update
this privacy policy as we undertake new personal data practices or adopt new privacy policies.
Applicability and Eligibility This privacy policy applies to our collection, use, disclosure, and protection of your data. It does not apply to third party websites, applications, or services. Before accessing, using, or interacting
with our services, carefully review the terms and conditions of this privacy policy. Services are not directed to children under the age of 16. You may not use our services if you are under the age of 16.
Collection and Use of Personal Information
We collect personal information about our members and other customers. This information includes, but is not limited to, first name, last name, job title, employer name, work address, work
email, and work phone number. This information is used to provide members and customers with goods and services, including membership services, event notifications, training, and more. We do not sell personal information to anyone and only share it
with third parties who are facilitating the delivery of our services.
Membership When you become a member, we collect information about you including (but not limited to) your name, your employer’s name, your work address, and your email address. We may also collect your personal email address, a personal
mailing address, and a mobile phone number. Members may voluntarily provide additional information in their membership profile, such as information about their educational background, number of years in the industry, and the like. Members may edit
their profile at any time to change, add, or remove personal information.
We process your personal information for membership administration, to deliver member benefits, and to inform you of our events, content, and other benefits or opportunities associated with your membership. We may also use this information to help us
understand our members’ needs and interests to better tailor our products and services to meet your needs.
Events and Webinars We host events throughout the year, including our annual conference, webinars, and trainings (collectively “events”). If you are a member and register for one of our events, we will access the information in your
member account to provide you with information and services associated with the event. If you are not a member and you register for one of our events, we will collect your name and contact information, which we will store in our database and use to
provide you with information and services associated with the event. If you are a presenter at one of our events, we will collect information about you including your name, employer and contact information, and photograph, and we may also collect
information provided by event attendees who evaluated your performance as a presenter. As an attendee, speaker, or sponsor/exhibitor, we will keep a record of your participation to provide you with post-event information including details on upcoming
events you may be interested in.
We reserve the right to use any photograph/video taken at our events, without the expressed written permission of those included within the photograph/video. We may use the photograph/video in publications or other media material produced, used or contracted
including but not limited to: brochures, invitations, books, newspapers, magazines, television, websites, etc. To ensure the privacy of individuals, images will not be identified using full names or personal identifying information without written
approval from the photographed subject.
Publications In addition to producing original content, we also subscribe to news feeds and blogs produced by others, which we often link to from our website. This means you may find yourself on our website or reading an email where
we will offer you a link to another organization’s website for additional relevant content. At these times, you will be leaving our website. We are not responsible or liable for content provided by these third party websites or personal information
they may happen to gather from you.
You may wish to subscribe to some of our publications without becoming a member. To receive our mailings/newsletters by email, you will need to create a profile with us, which involves providing us with at least your first name and last name, an email
address, and the country in which you live. We do not share this information with any third party other than to store the information in our database.
You may manage your subscriptions by subscribing or unsubscribing at any time. If you have any difficulties managing your email or other communication preferences, please contact us at odnetwork@odnetwork.org.
Correspondence Information If you correspond with us by email, the postal service, or other form of communication, we may retain such correspondence and the information contained in it and use it to respond to your inquiry; to notify
you of our conferences, publications, or other services; or to keep a record of your complaint, accommodation request, etc. Users may opt-out of receiving certain communications by following the unsubscribe process described in an email communication,
or by contacting our office directly.
Access to Your Information Certain tools and settings are provided to help you access, correct, delete, or modify your personal information.  We welcome you to contact us regarding the information we have collected about you,
including the nature and accuracy of the data collected about you, to request an update, modification, or deletion of your information, to opt-out of certain services, or to withdraw any consent you may have granted. Please note that if you choose
to delete your information or opt-out of the collection and use of your information, certain features may no longer be available to you.
Purposes for Processing Your Data As explained above, we process your data to provide you with the goods or services you have requested or purchased from us, including membership services, events, publications and other content, certification,
and training. We use this information to refine our goods and services to better tailor them to your needs and to communicate with you about other services we offer that may assist you in your career or otherwise help you to advance your career.
Payment Information We may collect and store information related to purchases if you choose to purchase goods and services from us. You may provide certain information to complete payments, including your credit or debit card number,
card expiration date, CVV code, and billing address (collectively, “Payment Information”), along with your name and billing, and shipping address, to complete payment transactions. Per PCI Compliance, we do not accept credit card information via email.
Credit card information received via fax, phone, or mail is entered into a secure system and then deleted and destroyed.
Website Usage As is true of most other websites, our website collects certain information automatically and stores it in log files. The information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, the region or general location where
your computer or device is accessing the internet, browser type, operating system and other usage information about the use of our website, including a history of the pages you view. We use this information to help us design our site to better suit
our users’ needs. We may also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our website, analyze trends, track visitor movements, and gather broad demographic information to assist us in identifying visitor preferences.
Our website also uses cookies and web beacons. It does not track users when they cross to third party websites or provide targeted advertising to them, and therefore does not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals.
Sharing Information
Information about your purchases are maintained in association with your membership or profile account. The personal information we collect from you is stored in a database hosted by a third party, YourMembership
(“YM”). YM does not use or have access to your personal information for any purpose other than cloud storage and retrieval.
We do not otherwise reveal your personal data to third-parties for their independent use unless: (1) you request or authorize it; (2) it’s in connection with any of our events as described above; (3) the information is provided to comply with the law
(for example, to comply with a search warrant, subpoena or court order), enforce an agreement we have with you, or to protect our rights, property or safety, or the rights, property or safety of our employees or others; (4) the information is provided
to our agents, vendors or service providers who perform functions on our behalf; (5) to address emergencies or acts of God; and (6) to address disputes, claims, or to persons demonstrating legal authority to act on your behalf.
Our website uses interfaces with social media sites such as Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter and others. If you choose to "like" or share information from our website through these services, you should review the privacy policy of that service. If you are
a member of a social media site, the interfaces may allow the social media site to connect your site visit to your personal data.
Member Directory Members are allowed to share their information through our Member Directory to other members using this site. Members are invited to opt-in to having their information shared in the Member Directory. Member information
will only be shared in the Member Directory if the member has opted-in to sharing such information.
Member Directory Do's and Don'ts
Do utilize the directory for professional networking purposes.
Do contact a member for insight, ideas, and general feedback on how to handle a particular issue.
Do contact members to discuss news and topics relevant to the field.
Do share content with members that is solely informative or educational.
Don’t make unsolicited contact with other members to describe or promote your business or services, or to make a sale.
Don’t use the directory to promote your clients.
Don’t use the directory contents to generate bulk communications, direct mail, or e-blast lists.
Don’t share the directory with third parties.
Member Directory Terms of Use
We encourage your use of the online membership directory
for professional networking purposes with your peers for guidance and
insight on best practices and experiences in the OD community.
However, you are not permitted to use the OD Network name, or the name of a
OD Network meeting, program, product, or service, in your communications
with directory organizations in a way that implies the OD Network participates in, or approves of, the communication, or that implies
OD Network endorsement or sponsorship of the content of your
communications, without prior Council approval in writing.
The directory may not be used to sell or market a business, product,
or service; to solicit contributions, sponsorships, or business
opportunities; or for any unlawful use. The contents of the directory
may not be used to generate mailing lists, e-mail lists, phone lists, or
other lists for any commercial purposes. You agree not to solicit the
members included on this list unless your solicitation is a direct
result of having obtained the members’ contact information from another
source in the ordinary course of your business. You agree not to release
or sell the directory or its contents to any third parties. Nothing
herein shall prohibit or limit the use of information generally
available to the public.
The OD Network reserves the right to change the contents, format, or
access of this directory or to discontinue it at any time, as well as
the right to deny access to the directory to any person or organization
the OD Network has reasonable grounds to believe may be using the directory
for an unlawful or unauthorized purpose. Check back periodically for
any modifications to the Terms of Use. Should you later object to the
Terms of Use or subsequent modifications, your only recourse is to
immediately discontinue your use of the directory. Your continued use of
the directory after any change constitutes acceptance of the change.
The contents of the directory are owned by and are the exclusive
property of the OD Network. Unauthorized use of the
directory is prohibited and can subject you to damages plus attorney's
fees. You acquire only a right to use the directory as authorized
herein, and not any right of ownership in the directory.
By accessing the directory, you are agreeing to these terms and conditions.
Changes and Updates to the Privacy Policy
By using this site, you agree to the terms and conditions contained in this privacy policy. As our organization, membership, and benefits change from time to time, this privacy policy is expected
to change as well. We reserve the right to amend the privacy policy at any time, for any reason, without notice to you, other than the posting of the amended privacy policy on our website. We may e-mail periodic reminders of our notices and terms
and conditions and will e-mail members of material changes.
Questions/Concerns? We are headquartered in St. Paul, Minnesota, in the United States. If  you have any questions or concerns about our data policies or practices, contact information is below:
Barb Mann Organization Development Network Director of Member Services 1000 Westgate Dr, Ste 252 St. Paul, MN 55114 USA Phone: +1 651-379-7292 Email: data@odnetwork.org
1000 Westgate Drive, Suite 252 Saint Paul, MN 55114 Phone: +1.651.379.7292 Fax: +1.651.290.2266
odnetwork@odnetwork.org
View our Data Privacy Policy
Sitemap
Copyright © 2020 Organization Development Network. All rights reserved.
What Is OD?
Membership Management Software Powered by YourMembership  ::  Legal
